I will now name
the successor to Ninshu.
The one who shall take over
Ninshu will be...
(ハゴロモ)では これより
忍宗の後継者を発表する。
Ashura!
忍宗の後継者は…。
L-Lord Hagoromo!
Why?!
I have nowhere near the skills for
Ninshu that Elder Brother has!
アシュラに任せる。
The difference is immeasurable!
(アシュラ)えっ!?
(インドラ)なっ！
I've made my decision.
Please tell me why you were
dissatisfied with me.
(フタミ)ハ… ハゴロモ様！
(アシュラ)なぜです!?
私には 兄さんほどの
忍宗の才はありません！
I received word that the village
I had left you in charge of
(ハゴロモ)これは 決めたことだ。
is near destruction.
(インドラ)なぜ 私では不満なのか
その理由をお聞かせください。
What? How?!
You didn't forcibly use
the Divine Tree to...
お前に任せた村は 今
壊滅状態にあるとの報告を受けた。
Do I look like a fool?
そんな… どうして!?
Tell me what you did.
まさか 神樹を無理やり…。
I did the same thing Ashura did.
私が そこまで愚かに見えるか？
I gave the people the water
they desired...
and dealt with the Divine Tree.
何をしたのか 話してみよ。
The only difference was that...
I did it alone.
私がやったことも
アシュラと同じです。
And that drastically affected the result.
望みどおり 村の者たちに
水を与え 神樹を処分した。
After you left,
ただ 違うのは 私は
１人でやった ということです。
the villagers fought over water rights
and ended up destroying themselves.
それが 大きく結果を変えたのだ。
Happiness obtained with
the easy way never lasts long.
村の人間たちは 水の利権を争い
自らの身を滅ぼしたそうだ。
But Ashura labored alongside
the people to open up a path.
Hard-earned happiness
is difficult to destroy.
楽をして 手にした幸福は
長続きはしないものだ。
だが アシュラは 村の人々とともに
苦難の道を歩いた。
Indra, you have a wonderful power
known as the Sharingan.
苦難のすえに手にした幸福は
そう簡単には崩れはしない。
Ashura has matured,
but still lacks in power.
Lend him your power going forward
and support the growth of Ninshu.
インドラ… お前には 写輪眼という
すばらしい力がある。
アシュラは成長したといえど
まだ 力は足りない。
これから先
忍宗を支えていくために→
アシュラに力を貸してやってくれ。
Elder Brother...
兄さん…。
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
The Successor
Why?
Why didn't he choose me?
Exactly!
The one with power rules the world!
That's just common sense!
((インドラ : なぜだ…
なぜ 俺が選ばれない？
Indra has the power
to decide everything!
Let's appeal to
Lord Hagoromo again.
そのとおりだ！
We'll support you!
力がある者が世界を制するのは
当たり前のことだ！
Thanks, both of you.
インドラには すべてを
決めるだけの力があるじゃないか。
No need for thanks.
We just want to support you.
今から もう一度
ハゴロモ様に かけ合ってみようぜ。
Yes, just tell us anything
that you want us to do!
俺たちも力を貸す。
(インドラ)すまない ２人とも。
Really?
いいんだ。 俺は ただ
お前の力になりたいだけだ。
あぁ なんでも言ってくれ。
This is amazing!
そうか…。
I've never seen such a feast!
Today is the auspicious day
the successor of Ninshu was chosen!
Everyone, eat and enjoy
to your heart's content!
(タイゾウ)うひょ～！
こんなご馳走 見たことねえ!!
Let's eat, everyone!
今日は 忍宗の後継者が決まった
めでたい日だ。
みんな！ 無礼講で
心ゆくまで楽しんでくれ。
食おうぜ みんな！
I think we came at a bad time.
Don't worry about it.
To be honest, I'm relieved.
(カンナ)なんだか 私たち
大変なときに来ちゃったみたいね。
That Ashura was chosen
to be the successor.
ヘッ！ 気にすること ねえよ。
Ashura's big brother is smart
and he's a genius with Ninshu,
実は 俺 ほっとしてるんだ
後継者が アシュラに決まって。
but there's a coldness to him.
If he was named successor,
I think we'd all be scared of him.
えっ？
(タイゾウ)アシュラの兄さんは 頭もいいし
忍宗の才能も すごいけど→
I see.
どっか
冷たいところがある人でさ…。
But Ashura understands a person's pain.
あの人が 忍宗 継いだら
みんな 心のどっかで→
He's a bit dense, but this last journey
really matured him.
ビクビクしてなきゃ
ならなかったと思う。
そうなんだ。
Enough to make you
fall in love with him
でも アシュラなら人の痛みがわかる。
and follow him all the way here.
W-What're you saying?!
ちょっとマヌケだけど 今度の旅で
あいつは すごく成長した。
You're blushing.
You idiot!
Ouch!
お前が惚れ込んで ここまで
ついてくるくらいにさ。
Really...
Hey, where is Ashura anyway?
何言ってんのよ。
赤くなってんぞ。
バカ！
あっ…。
もう。
そういえば アシュラ
どこ行ったんだろう？
Ashura...
You're not satisfied?
Yes.
アシュラか。
Indra has changed...
It's because of the Sharingan.
納得いかぬか？
はい。
Sharingan?
Everyone who sees Sharingan is
overwhelmed by its power.
インドラは変わってしまった。
写輪眼のせいでな。
And that happened
way before Indra realized it.
写輪眼が？
That's how powerful
Indra's Sharingan is.
インドラの写輪眼を見た
誰もが その力に圧倒される。
インドラ本人も気づかぬうちにな。
That power stopped Indra from
understanding how others feel...
それほどに インドラの写輪眼は
強力なのだ。
And in the end, it closed his heart.
その力ゆえに いつしか本人も
人の心を理解することをやめ→
But you are different.
You understand the human heart.
ついに
インドラの心は閉じてしまった。
That is why you enhanced
Ninshu with love.
And that nurtured trust among people,
created bonds and friendship.
だが お前は違う。
お前は人々の心を理解できる。
Friendship?
ゆえに愛をもって忍宗を生かした。
A bond is only created after
sharing hardship together.
それが人々の信頼を生み
絆を生み 仲間を生んだ。
A bond overflows with love
and compassion.
仲間…。
As long as there are bonds,
Ninshu will not be used for evil.
絆とは多くの苦楽をともにし→
初めて生まれるものだ。
However, power without bonds will
bring about calamity in the world.
絆には愛と情が溢れている。
絆があるかぎり 忍宗が
悪用されることはない。
Ashura...
Join forces with your brother and
spread the bonds of Ninshu.
だが 絆なき力は→
いずれ世界に災いを起こす。
Father...
アシュラよ。
From this moment onward,
I entrust my power to you.
お前は兄とともに ２人力を合わせ
忍宗の絆を広めるのだ。
父上。
Ashura!
これより お前に
わしの力を託す！
Where did he go?
アシュラ。
もう どこ行ったのかしら。
What is that?!
えっ…。
何 あれ？
W-What is it?
(みんな)うわ～。
Kanna! Are you all right?
Yes...
な 何だ？
What just happened?
カンナ 大丈夫か？
ええ。
いったい…。
Elder Brother!
Indra...
What is the meaning of this?
Why?
兄さん。
Why didn't you choose me
as your successor?
It isn't power that
controls Ninshu, but love.
インドラ これはどういうことだ？
That is what I have decided.
なぜだ なぜ俺が
後継者に選ばれない？
Love?
There is no need for love!
During my journey,
忍宗を統べるのは力ではなく愛。
そう決めたのだ。
like Ashura,
I searched for the villagers' pain.
But ultimately, the villagers
ended up relying on my power.
愛だと？ 愛など必要ない。
あの旅のとき
俺もアシュラと同じように→
The weak revered me as their king
and wanted my power.
村人たちに痛みを求めた。
Ashura was lacking.
しかし 村の連中は
結局 俺の力にすがったのだ。
That is why he found it necessary
to get the cooperation of others.
弱き者たちは
俺を王と崇め 力を求めた。
But I'm different!
I don't need the help of the weak.
アシュラは未熟だったゆえに→
I can use my power
and I can establish total order!
他人の協力を必要と
せざるをえなかっただけだ。
だが 俺は違う！
A world completely
devoid of conflict!
弱き者の助けなどいらない。
That's just like my mother, Kaguya...
この力を使い 力による
完全なる秩序をつくる。
Especially those with power,
must never forget the human heart.
争いのない完全なる世界だ。
それでは
我が母上 カグヤと同じだ。
People cannot progress
as swiftly as you can.
力を持つ者こそ
心を忘れてはならんのだ。
Those who cannot walk
at the same pace
can only fear power
that has no bond.
人々は
お前ほど早く進むことはできぬ。
People will not support
governance through fear.
Then I shall force them to obey.
歩みを
同じくできぬ者たちにとって→
Please stop, Elder Brother!
絆なき力とは恐怖でしかない。
You would have given
your life to protect me.
人々は恐怖による統治では
従わない。
That's how kind you once were!
Ashura...
I am no longer that man.
なら力ずくで従わせるだけだ。
やめてください 兄さん。
I cannot return to being him.
兄さんは 俺の命を
守ってくれるくらい→
Indra...
優しかったじゃないか！
Your eyes!
アシュラ
あの頃の俺とは違う。
We just want to support you.
もう後戻りはできぬのだ。
Yes, just tell us anything
that you want us to do!
(インドラ その目は！))
Really?
Thank you, both of you.
((俺は ただお前の力に
なりたいだけだ。
ああ なんでも言ってくれ。
(インドラ)そうか。
ありがとう ２人とも。
Indra... Why?!
うう！
Forgive me...
インドラ…。
どうして…。
Whenever I lose the ones
closest and dear to me...
(すまない))
my Sharingan evolves.
Indra!
So you've stooped that low...
《親しい者を失ったとき
写輪眼は進化する》
Please stop!
I don't want to fight you, Elder Brother!
Oh... fight me?
((インドラ そこまで堕ちたか。
You've become quite brave, Ashura!
もうやめてください
俺は兄さんとは戦いたくない。
You really think
you can take me on?
ほう 俺と戦うだと？
ずいぶんと偉くなったな アシュラ。
お前が 俺の相手になると
思っているのか？
What?!
何!?
うお～ は～！
A-Amazing!
That's the result of his training!
す すごい。
修業の成果だぜ！
You've become quite brave, Ashura!
But it's not enough to beat me!
な…。
少しは できるようになったか。
(だが その程度では
私には勝てん！))
Here I come.
This is power!
((いくぞ。
これが力だ！
Ashura?!
うわ～っ！
アシュラ！
Father!
Everyone!
Join forces!
父上！ みんな！
You have the audacity
to point your blade at me?
皆 力を合わせるのだ！
(みんな)うお～っ！
この俺に刃向かうとは。
The powerless can band together,
but it means nothing.
(みんな)うわっ！
Father, let me perform the last rites
for your fragile ideals!
フン… 力のない連中が
群れたところで 意味などない。
It's over!
Elder Brother!
父上
あなたの言う脆弱な理想に 今→
引導を渡してやる。
終わりだ！
兄さん！
This is...
ん？
The power of the Six Paths!
You inherited it?
Ridiculous!
これは…。
六道の力
お前が受け継いだというのか！
こしゃくな！
Everyone, lend Ashura your power!
ぐっ…。
皆 アシュラに力を貸してくれ。
Father!
Ashura, chakra is a power that
can link the hearts of many!
Everyone!
父上!?
アシュラ チャクラとは
多くの人の心をつなぐ絆の力だ。
I feel it... I can feel...
everyone's...
... power!
みんな…。
感じるよ… みんなの力を！
What?!
なに!?
What is this?
Elder Brother!
Ashura!
なん… だと…。
This is...
... the power of our bond!
兄さん！
ぐっ… アシュラ！
これが 絆の力だ！
ぐあぁ～！
Elder Brother!
Stay away!
Ashura...
くっ… うぅ…。
I will never...
兄さん。
寄るな！
acknowledge Ninshu... or you!
アシュラ… 俺は忍宗を…。
Elder Brother...
お前を決して認めぬ！
Soon after that,
I heard rumors that Indra established
a sect of Ninjutsu that idealized power.
(兄さん))
I recorded the misfortune that
the Sharingan brings about
(ハゴロモ)その後 風の噂でインドラは→
in the stone tablet.
However, Zetsu took advantage of it
力を理想とする
忍術の一派を作ったと聞いた。
and seems to have
been a total waste.
わしは写輪眼の持つ不遇を
石碑として残した。
しかし それはゼツに利用され→
Ashura...
It seems my time in this world
is coming to an end.
まったくの無駄に
なってしまったようだがな。
Father!
- Father!
- Grandpa!
((アシュラ どうやら わしも→
I was not able to guide
this world well...
天命を
まっとうするときがきたようだ。
That's not true!
父上！
お父様。
おじいちゃん。
We'll pass on your will to many,
many people through Ninshu, Father!
わしは この世界を
うまく導くことはできなかった。
But I leave behind some who will not...
そんなことはありません。
Indra came by last night.
父上の意志は
これからも忍宗によって→
多くの者たちに
伝わっていきます。
だが
そうでない者も残してしまった。
ゆうべ インドラがやってきた。
えっ。
Is that you, Indra?
Have you come to kill me?
There's no need for me
to do that anymore.
インドラか？
I came here
to end the future
of this hell disguised as Ninshu.
わしを殺しに来たのか？
ハッ もう
俺が手を下すまでもなかろう。
You have always feared
the power of my grandmother.
俺がここに来たのは→
And instead of trying to
understand this enormous power,
これから地獄と化す
忍宗の未来を突きつけるためだ。
you merely ran from it...
using love and bonds as a shield.
あなたは ずっと
祖母の力を恐れていた。
だが その強大な力を直視せず→
Your selfish misconception
will mar the future of Ninshu
ただ避けようとしていた。
with wars and calamities.
愛だの絆などという
詭弁を盾にしてな。
Until I destroy Ashura
and his brethren,
and wipe out Ninshu from
the face of this world,
あなたの
その身勝手な思い違いが→
I have no intention of
ever stopping my fight.
忍宗の未来に
戦いと災いを生むのだ。
Until I accomplish this,
俺は アシュラとその一族を
そして 忍宗を→
my soul will reincarnate and fight,
however long it takes!
この世界から滅ぼすまで
永久に戦いをやめるつもりはない。
それを成し遂げるためなら→
俺の魂は何度でも よみがえり
戦い続ける。
Forgive me.
Father, please be at peace.
If Elder Brother's soul will reincarnate
over and over again, so shall mine.
すまぬの…。
父上 ご安心ください。
Ashura...
I entrust the future of this world...
兄さんの魂が何度でも
よみがえるのなら→
... to you and your descendants...
私の魂もまた
何度でも よみがえりましょう。
アシュラ この世界の行方は→
Father!
Lord Hagoromo!
- Father!
- Grandpa!
お前たちと
その子孫に託すとしよう。
And as Indra warned,
the battle between them waged on,
(アシュラ)父上！
(フタミ)ハゴロモ様！
(カンナ)お父様！
おじいちゃん！))
never-ending,
over and over again.
(ハゴロモ)そして インドラの宣言どおり
２人の戦いは続いた。
These battles took the lives of many
comrades and kin on both sides.
長く 果てしなく 幾度となく。
Hate begat hate,
and it reached a point of no return.
The fighting continued even after
Ashura and Indra died
その戦いで
憎しみが憎しみを生み→
to the numerous reincarnates
of their souls.
もはや取り返しのつかぬほどに
膨れ上がっていった。
To you, Senju Hashirama,
and Madara Uchiha...
その戦いは アシュラとインドラが
死んでもなお続いた。
and now, to Naruto Uzumaki
and Sasuke Uchiha.
２人の魂は幾度も転生してな。
その末裔が お前
千住柱間と うちはマダラ。
Everyone...
You must do everything in your power
to save Naruto and Sasuke.
そして 今は
うずまきナルトと うちはサスケだ。
I have implicit faith
that these two will find
the true solution
皆の者たちよ。
to this fate of the shinobi
that has continued for so long.
なんとしても
ナルトとサスケを助け出すのだ。
わしは 確信している。
この２人こそ
長く続いた忍の因縁に→
真実の答えを出してくれると。
boku ni wa wakaru nda uso o tsuite iru kimi ga
I can tell when you're lying
naite ii yo koko ni zutto irukara
It's okay to cry because I'll always be here
sekaijuu ni koborete iru hontou no ai no kimochi
Feelings of true love spills out throughout the world
sagashidashite miushinatte yoake ga kuru no matteru
We search for it but lose it, while waiting for daybreak
migi no hoshi ni wa boku no namae o tsukete
The star on the right will bear my name
kimi ga yonde okureyo
Will you call out to it?
hidari no hoshi ni wa kimi no namae ga ne
The star on the left will bear your name
niau yo zutto soba ni irukara
It's perfect, because we'll always be together
There's only one S-rank mission
that we can do, ya know?
Nothing good happened
and we messed up before,
but it's a mission
that only we can do!
This is getting interesting...
I'm getting kind of excited for this!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"A Special Mission"
All right!
Let's begin the mission!